<metadata>
  <identifier>sute013</identifier>
  <title>Computer Pop</title>
  <description>Today the moniker of IJO is known for everybody who is into electronica music and his famous The Driw Play EP still lies in thousands of computers all over the world.

In 2004 21 years old artist from Klaipeda (the sea port of Lithuania) made his first steps on our Sutemos net label and released a wonderful The Driw Play EP. It was so successful so we can hear feedback about it until now. In 2005 two tracks from it were released on Pizza Jazz Music compilation which was compiled and released by a famous Lithuanian house duo RyRalio DJs.


After his debut on Sutemos IJO has become one of the most important participants of experimental electronica events and festivals. And no matter on what even IJO plays you can always hear people applauding while the tracks from The Driw Play EP are sounding. It still remains being one of the strongest and most popular releases by Lithuanian artist on Sutemos. Above from everything else some of his music is featuring other releases: his track has entered a recent Sutemos compilation Draumar Um Kalt Sumar (Sutemos) and two of his remixes can be found on debut single Contraction EP (Sutemos) of Lithuanian band FusedMARc.

Today IJO is back with his newest creation - Computer Pop album. As IJO himself talks about it "I know that everybody is looking forward to something like The Driw Play EP but I am not going to create such kind of music any more. I really donÃÂ¢ÃÂÃÂt want to and I am not afraid to disappoint anybody. I create music for myself but, of course, it is always to know that somebody appreciates what I do. Computer Pop EP is featuring the tracks that were created right after The Driw Play EP as I had the same mood. There are also some new tracks that retain the same range of colours. The rest of my releases will be totally different from this one".</description>
  <subject>IJO, sutemos, computer pop, easy listening, ambient</subject>
  <addeddate>2006-07-27 10:43:34</addeddate>
  <curation>[curator]malware@archive.org[/curator][date]20140312052255[/date][comment]checked for malware[/comment]</curation>
</metadata>
