<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <identifier>raam004</identifier>
  <type>sound</type>
  <publicdate>2004-07-10 07:26:03</publicdate>
  <creator>Holger Flinsch</creator>
  <description>holger flinsch from frankfurt (.de) is one of the rare artists which musical productions range between deepest ambient music and clubtechno. and yet he walks the genres with highest precision.

well known for his elektrolux/mikrolux release "regayov"
and for his various releases on labels like basalt, choke, eruptive, konfekt, phono elements, thinner and tongut.
his longplayers "collapsing new people" on punkt musik, and "der zehnte juli" on choke remain unforgettable. our pleasure to present his second netaudio release on this important date.

for realaudio.ch holger flinsch goes into static spheres reminding at the sound subtleness of a pete namlook, with beats and clicks vladislav delay and plastikman would certainly give a second listen.

"organon" consists of five tracks recorded in autumn 2003 at "the exile chamber" and "the underdoor" studios, musically glued into a story by the artist himself.
warm ambient at its best..


reviews:
Die Ambient Releases auf Realaudio lassen meine Aufmerksamkeit steigen. Nimmt man es doch in der Schweiz mit den Genregrenzen nicht ganz so eng. Holger Finsch tobt sich mit Orangon knapp 40 Minuten aus, es ist ein Track, der eigentlich aus 5 einzelnen Songs besteht, die zu einer Art Geschichte verpackt wurden, welche ich hier mal kurz darlege: Auf der Terrase des Cafe del Mar gehts los, wobei ich an längst vergangene Zeiten erinnert werde, als es dort noch nicht so abgeranzt war und Goa kein Schimpfwort. Fein, das sind die Grenzpfosten zwischen denen Holger hypnotisch und zielgenau den ersten Teil aufbaut, fliegen usw. Landung in der digitaliserten Natur und ordentlich Dub eingeworfen. Schön, wie bei dem Release Dub, Noise, Soundscapes und sogar IDM Beats einfliessen ohne direkt danach zu klingen. Eine sehr eigene Sache, vor allem die Mitte des Track knuspert fein und lullt auch den letzen Kieferartisten ein. 
datamat  for de:bug</description>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/</licenseurl>
  <date>2004-07-10 00:00:00</date>
  <title>Holger Flinsch - Organon [raam004]</title>
  <uploader>sgis@gmx.net</uploader>
  <addeddate>2004-07-10 06:27:30</addeddate>
  <adder>sgi_s</adder>
  <pick>1</pick>
  <runtime>00:39:04</runtime>
  <updatedate>2004-07-12 07:33:49</updatedate>
  <updater>sgi_s</updater>
  <notes>release page: http://www.realaudio.ch/amb/raam004.html</notes>
  <source>realaudio.ch</source>
  <public>1</public>
  <numeric_id>6938</numeric_id>
  <collection>realaudio</collection>
  <collection>netlabels</collection>
  <filesxml>Wed Sep 17 0:40:55 UTC 2014</filesxml>
  <boxid>OL100020216</boxid>
</metadata>
