<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <identifier>63_051</identifier>
  <type>sound</type>
  <publicdate>2004-07-13 21:12:57</publicdate>
  <creator>020200</creator>
  <description>Tomas Lipka aka monostatic with his first release on 2063music.de
Tomas also releases music under the name monoide, which focuses more on dancable technomusic, while monostatic does on listening electronics. Monoide made his debut in realaudio.ch netlabel with the album "periodt". "TanzKurs" is called his recently released mix on realaudio that gave us an insight of his technomixingabilities. This mix is really one of the most inspired technomixed i've ever heard in the last few years. He is also dedicated to the Slovakian techno- and electronicscene. Tomas Lipka is residenting in a Slovakian Techno-Club, called Ucko. His next Monoide-Release will be back on realaudio at 01aug2004 which is called 'Numbers'.

But this here is the first monostatic-release from Tomas Lipka. He does it exclusively for 2063music. The music unfolds in very digital layers with crackles and pulsating beats. Silent and linear motion. The sub drk introduxion pt.3+4 is my personal highlight of this ep with this very special mood, unique flavor and great beats.
A very gifted young artist, that will come through our speakers in 2004-2005!</description>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/</licenseurl>
  <date>0000-00-00 00:00:00</date>
  <title>monostatic - sub drk introduxion [63_051]</title>
  <uploader>mw@2063music.de</uploader>
  <addeddate>2004-07-13 11:03:51</addeddate>
  <adder>020200</adder>
  <pick>0</pick>
  <runtime>24min</runtime>
  <updatedate>2004-07-14 06:43:14</updatedate>
  <updater>020200</updater>
  <public>1</public>
  <subject>Electronic</subject>
  <numeric_id>6989</numeric_id>
  <collection>2063music</collection>
  <collection>netlabels</collection>
  <filesxml>Wed Sep 17 1:01:07 UTC 2014</filesxml>
  <boxid>OL100020000</boxid>
</metadata>
