<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>mtk-vol-1-the-early-years</identifier>
  <uploader>simon@archive.org</uploader>
  <addeddate>2013-02-03 07:11:37</addeddate>
  <title>Various Artists - Monotonik Vol.1: The Early Years</title>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <collection>monotonik</collection>
  <description>In the late '90s, Monotonik - an online free to download 'net.label' founded in 1996 and largely releasing .MOD 'tracker' files made in Amiga and PC formats, expanded to release in a brand new format - the MP3.

Drawing from artists worldwide linked by the Internet, and influenced by the rise of melodic, downtempo electronics from labels like Warp, Rephlex, and FAX, this first  compilation picks some of the best releases originally available via Monotonik in 1999 and 2000.

Spanning classic early Monotonik artists like Finnish ambient-electronics artist Lackluster (aka Distance), Australian electronica pioneers like Thug, Super Science, and Pretty Boy Cross Over, plus British stars of earlier Mono releases such as Hoffman and Vim!, the entire 19-track compilation whirs and hums with a quiet sinewave beauty that belies its increasing age.

This is the first in a series of compilation spanning the entire catalog of Monotonik, all Creative Commons licensed and free to download and stream.

Full tracklisting:

01. Jiva - Sous L'eau A Pied
02. Distance (aka Lackluster) - Gobblad
03. 3818919/w - Cheshire
04. Kuu - Contours Of Infinity
05. Lackluster - Bothersome (Mother Mix)
06. Hoffman - Rewired Electronics
07. Bearded Vault System - Selling Puppies From A Tray
08. 3818919/w - Ages
09. Thug - Obatem By Night
10. Sushi Brother - Shadowfighter (Frank &amp; Bill Remix)
11. Lindon - Eksajoule
12. Lackluster - 13/10/99
13. Vim! - Fit At The Front
14. Hoffman - Assault Systems
15. Thug - Sudafed x2
16. Sleepy - Foob
17. Radix - Counting Stars
18. Super Science - We're Like Air, Everywhere At Once
19. Pretty Boy Cross Over - Oranje Bloom</description>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</licenseurl>
  <collection>netlabels</collection>
  <publicdate>2013-02-03 07:13:00</publicdate>
  <filesxml>Tue Sep 16 23:44:11 UTC 2014</filesxml>
  <boxid>OL100020611</boxid>
</metadata>
