<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <identifier>mtk084</identifier>
  <type>sound</type>
  <publicdate>2003-07-08 08:20:14</publicdate>
  <description>We're very proud to present the first release on Monotonik from &lt;a href="mailto:len_of_rtm@the-any-key.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Secede&lt;/a&gt;, a Dutch-based artist who's just starting to get a lot of buzz online, with a remix featured on the hotly anticipated Machine Drum remix CD due out on &lt;a href="http://www.m3rck.net" rel="nofollow"&gt;Merck&lt;/a&gt; pretty soon, plus a full length solo CD (also on  &lt;a href="http://www.m3rck.net" rel="nofollow"&gt;Merck&lt;/a&gt;) to follow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So, this 4-track EP is a perfect introduction to the lush, melodic and intelligent sound of Secede, with the first track, "Depart &amp; Arrive", cutting up a gorgeous ambient waltz with the American president's strangely melodious ramblings about the situation in Afghanistan.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; From then on, things can only get better, with "Option Screen (Phantas)", bringing in an immaculately cowbell-infested hip-sway groove, almost Nightmares On Wax-esque in its nonchalance, and "Seafold" cutting up haunting melodies and wayahead chilled cuts. Finally, "I Can't Help Fearing You" is a spectacular mess of notes gelled into one nutritious, ambient parting whole.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So, whether you're a shover or a pusher (but a pusher's a jerk), shove yourself into the horizontal position and enjoy this EP - we're pretty sure we'll be hearing more of Secede. If only when he mails us to complain about this overblown, but very necessary song description ;) </description>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd-nc/1.0/</licenseurl>
  <date>0000-00-00 00:00:00</date>
  <title>Secede - Mommylove &amp; Daddypride EP [mtk084]</title>
  <uploader>h0l@mono211.com</uploader>
  <addeddate>2003-07-08 08:20:14</addeddate>
  <adder>simon c</adder>
  <pick>0</pick>
  <updatedate>2003-11-03 15:31:04</updatedate>
  <updater>simon c</updater>
  <public>1</public>
  <subject>Electronic</subject>
  <numeric_id>381</numeric_id>
  <collection>monotonik</collection>
  <collection>netlabels</collection>
  <filesxml>Wed Sep 17 0:47:59 UTC 2014</filesxml>
  <boxid>OL100020605</boxid>
  <album>Mommylove &amp; Daddypride EP</album>
  <artist>Secede</artist>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_releasegroup_id:6c0e1532-3f12-338b-9be9-2ea1f0876be0</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_release_id:0be5970d-a594-43ae-9dbc-c0dba774f142</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:discogs:release:233485</external-identifier>
</metadata>
