<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <identifier>mtk093</identifier>
  <type>sound</type>
  <publicdate>2003-07-08 08:27:49</publicdate>
  <description>After digging delightedly around in the archives, Monotonik is delighted to present the first of three 'virtual 7-inch' releases from Australian artist Super Science. All these tracks are taken from sessions done in 1999 for his super-limited Splashdown CDRs, and it's the first time they've been available anywhere besides those impossible to find releases.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For those of you who don't know Mark, aka Super Science, from his previous releases on Monotonik, his Splashdown CDRs were followed by an acclaimed album on &lt;a href="http://www.surgeryrecords.com.au" rel="nofollow"&gt;Surgery&lt;/a&gt;, "Love Like Life In Miniature", and that brought him to the attention of the US-based &lt;a href="http://www.anticon.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Anticon&lt;/a&gt; posse. Now called &lt;a href="http://www.cluetokalo.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Clue To Kalo&lt;/a&gt;, his CD/LP on &lt;a href="http://www.dirtyloop.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mush Records&lt;/a&gt;, "Come Here When You Sleepwalk", is out soon, and he's been playing live gigs using a band in Australia, ahead of touring with other Mush label peeps in the US and Europe in 2003. Plus, there's still rumors of a darncool European label picking the album up over there - more news as we get it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It only remains for us to swoon over the idyllic melodies and vocals of "You My Glimmering Satellite", plus quiver over the multi-tracked drift of "Samuel Crystal Bloom", and then hand you over to Super Science himself for his comments on the release - he'll be talking about each of these EPs as they're released. :)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;'When I started making music I used my computer and a Tascam 4-track cassette recorder. I played a song to someone and they suggested I burn some CD-Rs and sell them for $5 at the local record store. I did, and sold fifteen discs over a period of five months, all to people I knew. I was very rich.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When my CD came out on Surgery, we took a few of these old 4-track songs and put them on the album. Lots of them didn't make the cut. h0l is putting out some of those songs out as a series of virtual seven inches because he's a swell guy. I thought I'd give a blurb about each song because it will show that back then I mostly wrote songs to try and impress girls.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;'Samuel Crystal Bloom': This is a song that isn't about anyone. When I gave a tape of my music to a friend, this is the only one of the 17 songs he liked. After that, it always came first on any demo tape I made, because I assumed it was my 'good song'. Later I wrote a song that he thought was better, so this one was relegated to second place.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;'You My Glimmering Satellite': This song was written for a girl that I had a crush on. She didn't like me in 'that way', but I knew that all it would take to win her over would be a nice melodic electronic love tune. After I wrote it I recorded it on a tape and hurried round to her house. This should do the trick, I thought. We both sat in her living room and listened to it. It was the first time I'd sung on one of my tracks. After the song failed to impress her, I swore it'd be the last.' &lt;/i&gt;</description>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd-nc/1.0/</licenseurl>
  <date>0000-00-00 00:00:00</date>
  <title>Super Science - Doh EP [mtk093]</title>
  <uploader>h0l@mono211.com</uploader>
  <addeddate>2003-07-08 08:27:49</addeddate>
  <adder>simon c</adder>
  <pick>0</pick>
  <updatedate>2003-10-07 00:17:32</updatedate>
  <updater>simon c</updater>
  <public>1</public>
  <subject>Electronic</subject>
  <numeric_id>390</numeric_id>
  <collection>monotonik</collection>
  <collection>netlabels</collection>
  <filesxml>Wed Sep 17 0:47:43 UTC 2014</filesxml>
  <boxid>OL100020605</boxid>
  <album>Doh EP</album>
  <artist>Super Science</artist>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_releasegroup_id:96f23abf-3ec9-3f5d-87c7-32bbed79a89d</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_release_id:8c4249aa-4abf-4d42-9d4e-dd106419cfaa</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:discogs:release:258490</external-identifier>
</metadata>
