<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <identifier>mtk091</identifier>
  <type>sound</type>
  <publicdate>2003-07-08 08:26:23</publicdate>
  <description>The ever-fertile Australian electronic scene has spawned another gem, this time the offspring of an earlier Monotonik releaser, in the duo Toby1, comprising Ruth Wilson (vocals/instruments) and Duann Scott (composer/producer/instruments). Duann put out an earlier Monotonik release under his real name, and also released a warmly-received album on Surgery as part of Modula, and Ruth was formerly with cult Aussie band Masongreystrange.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Anyhow, the duo have been getting significant buzz down under, with an acclaimed live session for the Triple-J radio show, and we eagerly await their forthcoming debut on Surgery Records. But in the meantime, they've been kind enough to donate us a couple of stunning tracks to whet your appetite."European" is a gorgeously sustained lullaby of whispered thoughts, evoking perhaps Lamb, but with so much of a crunchier, chiseled edge, with the wistful vocals intoning "Let's go for a drive.. let's be European". And "Homely" twins mellow but stuttering drums with leaping synths and vocals so intertwined that there's literally a sea of sound to float in. "This feels like bliss", indeed..</description>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd-nc/1.0/</licenseurl>
  <date>0000-00-00 00:00:00</date>
  <title>Toby1 - European EP [mtk091]</title>
  <uploader>h0l@mono211.com</uploader>
  <addeddate>2003-07-08 08:26:23</addeddate>
  <adder>simon c</adder>
  <pick>0</pick>
  <public>1</public>
  <subject>Electronic</subject>
  <numeric_id>388</numeric_id>
  <updatedate>2005-12-07 00:01:18</updatedate>
  <updater>unix:etree</updater>
  <collection>monotonik</collection>
  <collection>netlabels</collection>
  <filesxml>Wed Sep 17 0:47:56 UTC 2014</filesxml>
  <boxid>OL100020605</boxid>
  <album>European EP</album>
  <artist>Toby1</artist>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_releasegroup_id:04334e21-797d-3479-a552-766d15467330</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_release_id:601d13a6-9017-4d28-90cd-7b19c395ab69</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:discogs:release:250501</external-identifier>
</metadata>
