<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <identifier>mtk095</identifier>
  <type>sound</type>
  <publicdate>2003-07-08 08:31:22</publicdate>
  <description>After numerous plaudits for the first EP Monotonik released from US-based &lt;a href="mailto:otoko_noko@hotmail.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Grandma&lt;/a&gt;, including 'Net-Audio Release of the Month' in cult German paper-magazine &lt;a href="http://www.de-bug.de/" rel="nofollow"&gt;De:Bug&lt;/a&gt;, we were keen to press on and put out some more material from the 15-year-old prodigy, who we think is one of the most amazing artists we've ever released on Mono.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This time, we've got a 4-tracker showcasing more of his diverse and eccentric talent, put together with just an old PC and rickety microphone, as before, but radiating lo-fi soul all the same.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The EP starts with "Abortions Rock", with the title belying a synth-wash-filled, stealthy drift through a multi-layered Garden Of Eden. Next, "Have Sex With A Tree" is a stupendously melodic magical carpet ride, like Squarepusher's 'Port Rhombus' on an even more polyhedral day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Next, "My God Is Better Than Yours" sets a sweet Grandma-plucked acoustic guitar loop and drapes strings, minimal drums, and intentionally lo-fi vocals over the top to heartfelt effect. And finally, yes, "Amazing Larry Does Not Bite Off Of Other Songs" does include an expressionless robotic voice rapping about 'biting off lines' from 'Ruff Ryder's Anthem'. What of it?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So what's the point? Maybe that this music is touching enough to make you feel good when you're in a bad place, and strong when you're in a weak place - and it's just the tip of the strangely skewed iceberg when it comes to Grandma's material, which richly deserves a wider audience still. We hope he gets it. </description>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd-nc/1.0/</licenseurl>
  <date>0000-00-00 00:00:00</date>
  <title>Grandma - Bopping Around In A Skin Car EP [mtk095]</title>
  <uploader>h0l@mono211.com</uploader>
  <addeddate>2003-07-08 08:31:22</addeddate>
  <adder>simon c</adder>
  <pick>0</pick>
  <public>1</public>
  <subject>Electronic</subject>
  <numeric_id>392</numeric_id>
  <updatedate>2005-12-07 00:01:19</updatedate>
  <updater>unix:etree</updater>
  <collection>monotonik</collection>
  <collection>netlabels</collection>
  <filesxml>Wed Sep 17 0:47:34 UTC 2014</filesxml>
  <boxid>OL100020605</boxid>
  <album>Bopping Around in a Skin Car EP</album>
  <artist>Grandma</artist>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_releasegroup_id:c9865198-3e82-35fb-9bac-3661b5ee234e</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_release_id:d40d69d5-ba5d-442e-aa1f-5ea16aa72653</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:discogs:release:258542</external-identifier>
</metadata>
