<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <identifier>mtk152</identifier>
  <type>sound</type>
  <publicdate>2005-09-10 18:32:21</publicdate>
  <creator>Tatsu</creator>
  <description>Having discovered Japanese techno artist Tatsu from his wonderful early work on his net.label Bumpfoot, we co-opted him to do an exclusive new EP on Monotonik, and the immensely lush 6-track 'August EP' is the result, showcasing the immensely pure, almost Detroit-tinged pastoral electronica - no tricks, no feints, just a trip back to the classics.

We start with 'Stillness/Introspective Me', which briefly showcases some gorgeous ambience, before moving straight into 'Sky and Sea/Daytime Dream', which sets the agenda - gently building, retro-percussive techno, with claps and hi-hats that sound like they're straight from 1985, but a purity of vision that make things shine. Going on, 'Highland/Glass and Mountains' is just amazing driving music- mechanical, straightahead and oddly almost Robert Miles-like, but avoiding trance cliches on the way to delirium. And so we continue on - 'Evening/Setting Sun' is if anything, even more bliss-like, with more trademark single-key melodies and an unplaceably backwards-looking tint, and 'Deep and Calm/Falling Asleep' works the goodness just a notch further, before 'Memories Of Summer/Goodbye' ends everything out with a gentle fade. More, please.
</description>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/</licenseurl>
  <date>0000-00-00 00:00:00</date>
  <title>Tatsu - August EP [mtk152]</title>
  <uploader>simon@archive.org</uploader>
  <addeddate>2005-09-10 18:19:12</addeddate>
  <adder>simon c</adder>
  <pick>1</pick>
  <updatedate>2005-09-10 18:33:06</updatedate>
  <updater>simon c</updater>
  <public>1</public>
  <publisher/>
  <runtime/>
  <source/>
  <taper/>
  <notes/>
  <collection>monotonik</collection>
  <collection>netlabels</collection>
  <filesxml>Wed Sep 17 0:48:02 UTC 2014</filesxml>
  <boxid>OL100020501</boxid>
  <album>August EP</album>
  <artist>Tatsu</artist>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_releasegroup_id:edfb8b3d-f1e5-3843-b9a9-605d09c3313d</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_release_id:033c0c8e-5a27-49ed-af3f-bfceda38045a</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:discogs:release:515672</external-identifier>
</metadata>
