<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>mtk161-wavespan</identifier>
  <title>Wavespan - Wavespan LP [mtk161]</title>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <collection>monotonik</collection>
  <description>Definitely one of the classiest Monotonik releases in a while, we're happy to slip sideways from our normal Scandinavian/European-influenced idm sound into a more ambient, sonorous, consciousness-expanded universe, thanks to Santa Cruz, California duo Wavespan, aka Phil Garrison and Alex Lumb, and their great self-titled debut LP.

Garrison started producing electronic music in 1998, and he founded Complex Logic Recordings, a small record label, in 2001. His production credits include Organic Resonance Project's Lucid EP and several remixes as ind01e; in 2005, he designed patches for H.G. Fortune's (VSTi) STS-21 Transition Synthesizer. Alex Lumb has been drumming for over 20 years, in addition to producing electronic music under various names. Most interestingly as a touchpoint, perhaps, this LP has been mastered by noted ambient musician Robert Rich, helping add to the carefully positioned ethereal drift.

Over the entire 49-minute LP, there are a plethora of high points, but many may be initially fascinated by a rare Monotonik-released dub track up front, in the form of the sparse 'Concentration Dub', before the epic 11-minute long 'On The Nature Of Consciousness' takes us away with almost Orb-like spoken word samples and some beautifully placed ambience. Other highlights include the mild paranoia of the JFK assassination-sampling 'Single Bullet Theory', the straight-ahead groove of 'Origin Of Species', and the marvellously placed groove of 'Momentary Bliss'.

Overall, this is a startlingly professional album which, honestly, almost feels too good for Monotonik, but we're delighted to release it nonetheless. If you like it, you can visit &lt;a href="http://www.complexlogicrecordings.com/wavespan.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;Wavespan's page on the Complex Logic site&lt;/a&gt; and order a copy of the CD, or simply donate funds of your choice via PayPal to compensate for the more than pleasant listening experience. Hurrah.</description>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/</licenseurl>
  <publicdate>2006-02-19 17:44:22</publicdate>
  <addeddate>2006-02-20 01:43:52</addeddate>
  <uploader>simon@archive.org</uploader>
  <updater>simon c</updater>
  <updatedate>2006-02-19 17:45:25</updatedate>
  <notes>"quite simply one of the best ambient releases on any netlabel to date."
-Alex Young, Milieu
 
"You step into it where you may and find something different each time. Fabulous stuff."
-Mark Teppo, Igloo Magazine</notes>
  <updatedate>2006-09-09 18:27:41</updatedate>
  <updater>simon c</updater>
  <boxid>OL100020613</boxid>
  <collection>netlabels</collection>
  <album>Wavespan</album>
  <artist>Wavespan</artist>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_releasegroup_id:c6f08879-8a6a-34f1-af3d-9f286886a60e</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_release_id:66f61740-fada-46d3-9503-092f05d3160d</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:discogs:release:651004</external-identifier>
</metadata>
