<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>mtk190</identifier>
  <title>Muxu - Show Us Your Weak Side [mtk190]</title>
  <creator>Muxu</creator>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <collection>monotonik</collection>
  <collection>netlabels</collection>
  <description>This new release is most definitely Monotonik's  first from Malaysia, thanks to duo Euseng and  Liang, also known as Muxu, who've followed up  their self-released debut album 'Above Us, A  Clear Summer Sky' with this wonderful 6-track  EP, 'Show Us Your Weak Side', here as the 190th  release on Mono.

The duo first met for a joint band project -  with Liang playing guitar for delightfully  named band Citizens of Ice-Cream, but set up  Muxu in early 2006. They've also contributed a  track to the Mu-nest label compilation 'We Are  All Cotton-Hearted', alongside other artists  such as Lullatone, Piana, Park Avenue Music and  Aus.

In any case, Muxu starts out with the  delightfully meandering 'Hishiko', all sliding  ambience and strong melodies -  reminding of  previous Monotonik artists Sleepy Town  Manufacture through a distinct guitar-infused  Asian blend, perhaps? It only gets lusher from  there, with 'Let's Walk On The Frozen Sea'  weaving almost Harold Budd-esque piano into the  mix, and 'Meeting Snow During Summer'  continuing the carefully multi-layered shimmer.

Other highlights include the careful groove of  'Moving At 30' and the end track, 'People  Running Away', which has us running towards,  not from Muxu's lush sound from an unusual  place. Thanks, guys.</description>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</licenseurl>
  <publicdate>2007-09-03 00:55:17</publicdate>
  <addeddate>2007-09-03 00:54:55</addeddate>
  <uploader>simon@archive.org</uploader>
  <updatedate>2007-09-03 00:55:56</updatedate>
  <updater>simon c</updater>
  <filesxml>Wed Sep 17 3:48:55 UTC 2014</filesxml>
  <album>Show Us Your Weak Side</album>
  <artist>muxu</artist>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_releasegroup_id:ecf02ec1-66d8-3a34-a445-3b3496a1482a</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_release_id:c3ee3025-7288-4386-9c95-eaa54d72ad55</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:discogs:release:1059234</external-identifier>
  <boxid>OL100020400</boxid>
</metadata>
