<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <identifier>mtk120</identifier>
  <type>sound</type>
  <publicdate>2003-10-25 17:37:17</publicdate>
  <description>It's been a while since semi-reclusive, wholly-gifted English electronica wonk Vim! has graced us with his presence. In his absence from Monotonik, he's remixed Machine Drum for a Merck release, had that track released on vinyl and on a Japanese mix-CD from Joseph Nothing's label, and, we hear, eaten a lot of baked beans and sausages. So, to help celebrate the launch of his brand-new CDR, '&lt;a href="http://www.vimster.demon.co.uk/cdr" rel="nofollow"&gt;A Random Collection Of Consonants&lt;/a&gt;', we're proud to release this EP, with two tracks from the CDR, and two bonus exclusive remixes of his earlier work - hence the title.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Startin off on the good foot, 'Trivial Machine' uses Vim's trademark, obtuse sinewave melodies along with weird counting-down effects, pixelated explosions, and general madness. On the other hand, 'Exists In Bad Sectors (FuzzDrop)' is a beguiling loopy piece of ambient style, whereas 'Could Cut Keys', the second piece from the CDR, has washes of static, beautifully strident dischord in the leads, and a sound which still sounds like absolutely nobody else. For a coda, we get '1994 Gold (via Ratners)' ordered up, all mordant and precise and hollow and just right.</description>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd-nc/1.0/</licenseurl>
  <date>0000-00-00 00:00:00</date>
  <title>Vim! - Remixconsonantthing EP [mtk120]</title>
  <uploader>h0l@mono211.com</uploader>
  <addeddate>2003-10-25 17:37:17</addeddate>
  <adder>simon c</adder>
  <pick>0</pick>
  <updatedate>2003-10-26 06:54:45</updatedate>
  <updater>simon c</updater>
  <public>1</public>
  <subject>Bleep</subject>
  <numeric_id>1120</numeric_id>
  <collection>monotonik</collection>
  <collection>netlabels</collection>
  <filesxml>Wed Sep 17 0:48:00 UTC 2014</filesxml>
  <boxid>OL100020605</boxid>
  <album>Remixconsonantthing EP</album>
  <artist>Vim!</artist>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_releasegroup_id:3b35016b-d6ef-3d18-98ed-429ebbcb0bd7</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_release_id:f80601f6-d1b3-4bd1-b52f-0b803a9f919c</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:discogs:release:233321</external-identifier>
</metadata>
