<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <identifier>mtk127</identifier>
  <type>sound</type>
  <publicdate>2004-02-29 12:19:46</publicdate>
  <creator>Blisaed</creator>
  <description>Returning after his debut 'As Time Passes EP' of last year, US electronic artist Matt Centonze, aka &lt;a href="http://www.blisaed.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Blisaed&lt;/a&gt;, who's been continuing to release excellent material on netlabels such as &lt;a href="http://camomille.genshimedia.com/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Camomille&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.ronincollective.com/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Ronin Collective&lt;/a&gt;, graces us with another gently beautiful 4-track EP of vocal-specked, emotion-tinged electronics. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; This time round, debut song 'Photo' starts things off with casually gorgeous melodies, all multi-layered and shimmering and oxidizing slowly as it's exposed to the air, before 'A Silent Walk In The Park' kicks in, whisper-sung vocals, longing, and odd beauty to the fore. From there on, 'The One You Thought You Knew' hits up a stop-start, almost Super Science-like groove of understated splendor, before 'Showing Her What You're Made Of' ends up with an even more herky-jerky, hyperreal mix of attractive keyboards and gently caressing synths. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; So, 'Hopeless Falling From EP' makes a lot of sense, both as another document of the resurgence of melodic electronic music in the U.S., and as a Monotonik release that fits into our sekrit agenda of releasing ths most gorgeous headphone music we can possibly find, and then spraying it out to the general public in a machine-gun fashion. Catch this one in your teeth, willya? </description>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd-nc/1.0/</licenseurl>
  <date>0000-00-00 00:00:00</date>
  <title>Blisaed - Hopeless Falling From EP [mtk127]</title>
  <uploader>h0l@mono211.com</uploader>
  <addeddate>2004-02-29 12:19:46</addeddate>
  <adder>simon c</adder>
  <pick>0</pick>
  <updatedate>2004-02-29 13:11:26</updatedate>
  <updater>simon c</updater>
  <public>1</public>
  <numeric_id>3778</numeric_id>
  <collection>monotonik</collection>
  <collection>netlabels</collection>
  <filesxml>Wed Sep 17 0:47:34 UTC 2014</filesxml>
  <boxid>OL100020103</boxid>
  <album>Hopeless Falling From EP</album>
  <artist>Blisaed</artist>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_releasegroup_id:5597d68f-50f9-39f0-8dbc-275ca65e4048</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_release_id:33743626-0e5d-4d3e-8c1b-bf3662d5c26d</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:discogs:release:237528</external-identifier>
</metadata>
