<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <identifier>mtk123</identifier>
  <type>sound</type>
  <publicdate>2004-01-01 23:45:03</publicdate>
  <description>Welcome to Monotonik's brand new year, courtesy of a debut release (or is it?) from Finn and self-proclaimed cosmic superspy, Aleksi Virta. He fearlessly busts out this supremely accomplished album of jazzy, dubby electronics, originally released on a scandalously limited, horrendously collectible 100-copy sold-out CDR edition, and now, thankfully available to the general public via the wonders of the Internet.

So basically, we're looking at everything from the headnodding organ jam of 'Nebulae Herb', through the incredible skank of 'Whirlwind Pistols Dub', even up to the end-theme beauty of 'Princess Melodiae'. Isn't it almost unseemly that this is a valiant attempt to snatch album of the year, and it's only January 1st? Cheeky, that's what we call it. In the meantime, you can read the helpful information which came in the CDR packaging:

'Our interstellar secret agent superhero rids the world of the evil curse of the misunderstood vicious madman (yet again) - starring: Aleksi Virta as the heroic secret agent extravaganza, Gavrila Nebula as the beautiful action heroine, Torsti as the misunderstood evil scientist madman, Carolina as the mysterious space gypsy princess.'

..and, indeed, you can learn more about Aleksi Virta's spacecapades via his &lt;a href="http://www.zion15.net/aleksivirta/diary/" rel="nofollow"&gt;twisted chroniclings&lt;/a&gt; - and long may they continue.</description>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd-nc/1.0/</licenseurl>
  <date>0000-00-00 00:00:00</date>
  <title>Aleksi Virta - ..Meets Torsti At The Space Lounge [mtk123]</title>
  <uploader>h0l@mono211.com</uploader>
  <addeddate>2004-01-01 23:45:03</addeddate>
  <adder>simon c</adder>
  <pick>0</pick>
  <updatedate>2004-03-04 16:40:27</updatedate>
  <updater>simon c</updater>
  <public>1</public>
  <subject>Electronic;Jazz+Funk;Neo-cosmic</subject>
  <numeric_id>1945</numeric_id>
  <collection>monotonik</collection>
  <collection>netlabels</collection>
  <filesxml>Wed Sep 17 0:48:02 UTC 2014</filesxml>
  <boxid>OL100020605</boxid>
  <album>...Meets Torsti at the Space Lounge</album>
  <artist>Aleksi Virta</artist>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_releasegroup_id:66eef5e5-d9a3-3a74-ac09-bbcc2c81c845</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_release_id:280af2c7-9c89-40e4-af5a-cb5742cc991d</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:discogs:release:258516</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:discogs:master:372360</external-identifier>
</metadata>
