<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <identifier>mtw023</identifier>
  <type>sound</type>
  <publicdate>2003-07-08 11:46:09</publicdate>
  <description>After the unexpected and tragic loss of Andi Horvath, aka Ramone/Mono, of a sudden heart failure in June (tribute page &lt;a href="http://www.mono211.com/content/ramone.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), we at Monotonik+friends were contacted by his friends at &lt;a href="http://www.fruitz-of-dojo.de" rel="nofollow"&gt;Fruitz Of Dojo&lt;/a&gt; (the Mac demo-scene group he was a member of) with a number of great unreleased Ramone .XM tracks (playable in WinAmp) which had been composed, in the months before he passed away, for both a demo ('Fistful Of Dojo') and a 'chip' music-disc ('SuperSIDekick Sessions').&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So, we're proud to present these 16 unreleased .XM tracks, totalling 1.3meg in .ZIP form, as the first part of Andi's musical legacy (the second, upcoming installment is his unreleased 1998 full-length album, originally done for Germany's Firehorse Records.) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The release is divided into two parts, with the 3 tracks for the 'Fistful Of Dojo' demo encompassing intense funk through super-hard shaolin hiphopjungle action, and the remaining chip-tunes from the 'SuperSIDekick Sessions' doing wonderful chipped-up funky action with electro-hiphop influences, all in under 30k per track. It's spectacularly vibrant stuff, and makes us all happy and kinda melancholy at the same time - when all is said and done, your music rocks, and always will, Andi. </description>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd-nc/1.0/</licenseurl>
  <date>0000-00-00 00:00:00</date>
  <title>Ramone - Unreleased Works Part 1 - The Fistful Of Dojo and SuperSIDekick Sessions [mtw023]</title>
  <uploader>h0l@mono211.com</uploader>
  <addeddate>2003-07-08 11:46:09</addeddate>
  <adder>simon c</adder>
  <pick>0</pick>
  <updatedate>2003-07-08 11:47:06</updatedate>
  <updater>simon c</updater>
  <public>1</public>
  <subject>Electronic</subject>
  <numeric_id>432</numeric_id>
  <collection>monotonik</collection>
  <collection>netlabels</collection>
  <filesxml>Wed Sep 17 0:47:46 UTC 2014</filesxml>
  <boxid>OL100020605</boxid>
</metadata>
