<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>12rec.037</identifier>
  <title>Nic Bommarito - Taciturn [12rec.037]</title>
  <creator>Nic Bommarito</creator>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <description>Nic Bommarito comes off like the all-American college boy. He's from a small city in the near distance to Detroit, Michigan. He studied philosophy in Ann Harbor and changed to Albuquerque, New Mexico to expand his Sanskrit-studies. This trip took him across 2/3 of the US, but the next relocation was even more thoroughgoing . In 2006, Nic moved to Lhasa in Tibet, Republic of China.
Nic is the unresting type. Due to his studies, he runs several websites, draws small comic strips, releases philosophical prose and documents his travels via a nice photo-blog. What's interesting for you: Nic Bommarito is a talented musician, too. He got in contact with us in late 2006, and we spontaneously decided to release his Taciturn LP at 12rec.

The Taciturn LP fuses instrumental Rockmusic with moments of Alt. Country and epic Indiepop, keeping an eye on melody and structure. Imagine a mixture of Canadian GY!BE, the Americana Avant-Garde of Chicago's Brokeback and the huge melodies of Italian Postrockers Giardini di Mirò. Nic might not be the perfect musician, but he knows how to build up a song. For example, Taciturn I lasts nearly 10 minutes but you won't regret any single second. There's a strong sense of yearning throughout the whole LP that invokes a lot of pictures. Badly Asbestos-Covered sounds like desert and sea at the same time, bringing together slide guitar and accordion. The heavy string-arrangement for the final track I Never Listen is among the most touching I've ever heard.</description>
  <date>2007-01-28</date>
  <year>2007</year>
  <subject>Nic Bommarito;12rec;12rec.net;Instrumental,Guitar,Shoegaze;Indie;Electronic;Atmospheric;Introspective;Dreampop</subject>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.5/</licenseurl>
  <pick>1</pick>
  <public>1</public>
  <publicdate>2007-01-27 18:45:03</publicdate>
  <addeddate>2007-01-27 18:40:45</addeddate>
  <uploader>headquarter@12rec.net</uploader>
  <updater>Simon12rec.</updater>
  <updater>Simon12rec.</updater>
  <updater>Simon12rec.</updater>
  <updatedate>2007-01-27 19:01:57</updatedate>
  <updatedate>2007-01-27 19:12:49</updatedate>
  <updatedate>2007-01-27 19:35:59</updatedate>
  <taper>Nic Bommarito</taper>
  <source>www.12rec.net</source>
  <runtime>45:12</runtime>
  <updatedate>2007-01-29 07:01:35</updatedate>
  <updater>Simon12rec.</updater>
  <collection>12rec</collection>
  <collection>netlabels</collection>
  <filesxml>Wed Sep 17 1:01:45 UTC 2014</filesxml>
  <boxid>OL100020402</boxid>
  <album>Taciturn</album>
  <artist>Nic Bommarito</artist>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_releasegroup_id:6d790af1-4726-3699-8e2e-1f4c1894fee0</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_release_id:2939ff4b-ee0f-4823-9614-d9ba5bc78465</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:discogs:release:1198838</external-identifier>
</metadata>
