<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>12rec.033</identifier>
  <title>[12rec.033] Heezen - Secret Speech</title>
  <creator>Raül Fuentes</creator>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <collection>12rec</collection>
  <collection>netlabels</collection>
  <description>Heezen is Raül Fuentes. He's a non-musician from the city of Castello in the east of Spain. As he told me, Eno was a non-musician. Satie also didn't study it. 

Raül extracts the technique of sampling old vinyl-records from hip hop and combines it with minimal synthesizer- and guitar-loops, a lot of bizarre found-sounds, fragments of vocals and a few drops of psychedelica. there's some kind of strange musique concrète-atmosphere in his tracks that makes me think of late 60's avantgarde films and ambiguous surrealists like René Magritte, Man Ray or collagist Max Ernst. His loops are like spirals of fireworks that interfere with each other to build new patterns of sounds and melody. 
On his Secret Speech EP, Raül combines two sets of tracks he already released one on his own: Fractura, Pirotecnia and Martin De Vivies are in the middle of the EP. These tracks got a pretty straight beat and intensify layer-by-layer. Raül bridges from electroacoustic minimal-music to deep house, home-grown electronica and back. For the other three tracks, Raül comes up with a more ambient vibe. You can find pulsing synthesizers (Secret Speech), a complex composition of guitar, certain glitches, sampled vocals and a string section (Lastre) and the smooth, introspective cut-up collage of Le Cannard that marks the end of the EP.

Heezen created a dark sparkling gem of electroacoustica. His influences are legion, but due to his abilities as a sound-designer and songwriter, he managed to destillate them all in highly conclusive compositions that never forget about a certain amount of catchyness and, yeah, emotionality.</description>
  <date>2006-09-19</date>
  <year>2006</year>
  <subject>12rec;Heezen;Electronic;Elektronika;Laptop</subject>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.5/</licenseurl>
  <pick>1</pick>
  <public>1</public>
  <publicdate>2006-09-19 19:48:52</publicdate>
  <addeddate>2006-09-19 19:47:58</addeddate>
  <uploader>headquarter@12rec.net</uploader>
  <updater>Simon12rec.</updater>
  <updater>Simon12rec.</updater>
  <updatedate>2006-09-19 20:01:42</updatedate>
  <updatedate>2006-09-19 23:58:21</updatedate>
  <taper>Heezen</taper>
  <source>www.12rec.net</source>
  <runtime>27:15</runtime>
  <updatedate>2006-09-20 11:11:40</updatedate>
  <updater>Simon12rec.</updater>
  <filesxml>Wed Sep 17 1:21:48 UTC 2014</filesxml>
  <boxid>OL100020411</boxid>
  <album>Secret Speech</album>
  <artist>Heezen</artist>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_releasegroup_id:1074c029-095e-384a-b0f7-e6ee26fbe8ae</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_release_id:bdfc3627-ed92-4a0a-8572-86295754689f</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:discogs:release:861999</external-identifier>
</metadata>
