<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>12rec.039</identifier>
  <title>herzog - ocean! be our blanket [12rec.039]</title>
  <creator>Bill Bawden</creator>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <description>I recognized young Herzog a bit later than I could have. Being an important part of the Welsh Serein-collective, he contributed a wonderful piece of electro-acoustic ambient for the second label compilation OIO which, in a whole, was enjoyed a lot at the 12rec. world headquarter. We got the Crepusculum EP in the pipe and planned to add a remix to give Fred Batys' folklore music a decent electric twist. So we got in contact with Bill Bawden a.k.a. Herzog. His idea of transforming analogue sounds into short-form ambient-compositions fit our intentions perfectly.

After the great success of 12rec.036 back in December 2006, Bill told us about some new stuff he was preparing for a future release. In addition to the songs on both of the Serein -samplers he had two EPs online and we were happy to have the man for a special 12rec-release. Ocean! Be our Blanket consists of eight relatively short pieces each built around a single musical element or sound-idea. For In the Background, Secret Armies Bill distills the cozy melancholia of a delayed piano-motive with warm cracklings and low-key synthesizers. Woke Up Surrounded by Enemies has a rather ominous feel. You'll recognize the beautiful noises (some kind of Herzog-trademark), but there are no ‘real' instruments to be heard. Bubbling loops of synth-drones interfere, swell up and fade like a bad dream. The piano is back at Here Come Our Fathers afterwards. Bill opens his sound-repertoire a bit and shifts microscopic loops and distorted vocal samples in the wide echo chamber of his piano strokes. Listen to Adjusting to the Light to catch Herzog fusing guitar- or harp-sounds with some well-defined rhythmic elements. Crisp! If you want to hear one of my odd comparions- think of Pharrell Williams remixing Gastre Del Sol. Huh?

Warm, quite focused, hypnotic and neat. Herzog delivers a beautiful study on sound and structure that surprises with emotional discernibility and uniqueness. An experimental release for 12rec. after so much popmusic recently, but a record you shouldn't have missed.</description>
  <date>2007-05-18</date>
  <year>2007</year>
  <subject>herzog;Bill Bawden;12rec;12rec.net;electronic;electroacoustic;ambient</subject>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licenseurl>
  <pick>1</pick>
  <public>1</public>
  <publicdate>2007-05-18 14:36:57</publicdate>
  <addeddate>2007-05-18 14:22:11</addeddate>
  <uploader>headquarter@12rec.net</uploader>
  <updater>Simon12rec.</updater>
  <updater>Simon12rec.</updater>
  <updater>Simon12rec.</updater>
  <updatedate>2007-05-18 14:51:23</updatedate>
  <updatedate>2007-05-18 15:56:44</updatedate>
  <updatedate>2007-05-19 16:45:31</updatedate>
  <taper>Bill Bawden</taper>
  <source>www.12rec.net</source>
  <runtime>30:18</runtime>
  <updatedate>2007-05-19 19:21:54</updatedate>
  <updater>Simon12rec.</updater>
  <collection>12rec</collection>
  <collection>netlabels</collection>
  <filesxml>Wed Sep 17 19:03:26 UTC 2014</filesxml>
  <album>Ocean! Be Our Blanket</album>
  <artist>Herzog</artist>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_releasegroup_id:5b4e562f-e8a5-3cef-b6e5-f0093f12ba5a</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_release_id:555dfc55-5d12-4f6d-9435-0d4ac64274b7</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:discogs:release:1825006</external-identifier>
  <boxid>OL100020102</boxid>
</metadata>
