<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <identifier>12rec.021</identifier>
  <type>sound</type>
  <publicdate>2005-07-25 17:05:34</publicdate>
  <creator>VA</creator>
  <description>
after nearly one year of 12rec-music, we would like to say *thank you* to everybody that supported us, said hello or just grabed the MP3s. we're happy to be here.
this online-sampler contains loads of exclusive material we compiled from the secret 12rec-archives. just scroll down for the individual download. additionally, we added sort of a DJ-mix of this sampler to the open audio archive. get the sven swift mix if you like it better this way.

the love songs w/ wixel
hornets (radio edit) - preview
the love songs is one of the first 12rec-artists. the new EP will features four or five tracks of warm and noisy drone-music. metal machine music for airports, in his own words.

und morgen, der asphalt
da sind nur wir und sonst nichts - preview
und morgen, der asphalt is a project out of the highly creative tupolev-sourroundings. this vienna-based band combines strange german no-wave sounds with folk and pop-influences. EP out on 12rec soon.

fuellsand
meer und weizen - exclusive track
this new track shows the direction fuellsand are heading right now. there is more noise within the composition, still its quite dense and melodic. elektro krautrock, like rupert says.

milhaven
we talk, we die (new years edit) - exclusive track
milhaven will be famous sometime, promised! sven added organ, piano and field-rec to this studio-track the band recorded short after the bars closing down session with sebastian 'the hat' behler.

skism
surfaise - preview
david grogan is skism. this ireland-based guy combines melodic electronica elements with tight hip hop-beats. call it bleep hop or whatever, david knows how to write a catchy song. retrospective EP out on 12rec very soon!

sichtbeton
mecklenburg EP - excerpt
in 2002, as legends say, lunte (MC of berlin hip hop duo sichtbeton) produced the mecklenburg EP on his own, being isolated somewhere in eastern germany. get the whole 30 minutes EP at funkviertel.de.

moritz grund
induvish - taken from orange album
cologne producer moritz grund comes up with a colourful arrangement of differnet styles of electronic music. the whole album is avaible at legoego.de, get the CDR at the 12rec-shop.

tupolev
garlic (live in vienna) - exclusive track
recorded at the fluc in 2004, this long song will catch your attention. tupolev settle between folk, slooow postrock and avantgarde-music. dont be afarid of vienna people chating!

jasmin
new tayyabs (demo) - exclusive track
one of munics finest postrock-bands. the rehersal-recorded song you can hear on this sampler is quiete unusual for jasmin. simply a small gem of pop-music! EP02 out on 12rec soon.

engine 7
it was nice to be alive (but I really must be going home) - preview
alan mcNeill from glasgow will re-releas his hope street EP on legeoego.de very soon. the engine 7 sound is a hypnotizing mixture of trip hop beats and postrock melodies, very special. CDR on 12rec.

yokölast
spasern/ lachette (director's cut) - exclusive mix
cologne back again! a special mix of the on marx/ mosp EP's last two tracks destilizes everything artist yokölast stands for: electronic experiments and cheerish pop-melodies.

rob steady
exemples de retenues - taken from miettes EP
cut-up genious stèphane obadia with a song from the ask no lies prequel 'miettes'. he derives strange, somehow danceble pop-tracks from the big pile-up of commercial music. see clumsybeats.org for more obadia-madness!

zeugwart hallbauer
datteln - preview
sven hahne and alexander peterhaensel of jasmin are zeugwart hallbauer. their music is a unique mixture of jazzy tekhouse, hip hop and acid-like sounds. once again, the EP will include a video by peterhaensel.

giraffe
camoflaughed killer (demo) - exclusive track
after the sweet dusty windows EP, james gardner aka giraffe will release his album bull fighter at 12rec in a few months. this song is one of the many demos he sent us to get an impression.

</description>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.5/</licenseurl>
  <date>2005-07-26 00:00:00</date>
  <title>VA - Keepin´ It Real In 2005 [12rec.021]</title>
  <uploader>headquarter@12rec.net</uploader>
  <addeddate>2005-07-25 04:25:32</addeddate>
  <adder>Simon12rec.</adder>
  <pick>1</pick>
  <runtime>73:30</runtime>
  <updatedate>2005-07-28 06:24:31</updatedate>
  <updater>Simon12rec.</updater>
  <source>www.12rec.net</source>
  <taper>VA</taper>
  <public>1</public>
  <publisher>VA</publisher>
  <notes/>
  <collection>12rec</collection>
  <collection>netlabels</collection>
  <filesxml>Wed Sep 17 1:01:39 UTC 2014</filesxml>
  <boxid>OL100020511</boxid>
  <album>Keepin' It Real in 2005</album>
  <artist>Various Artists</artist>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_releasegroup_id:356a1a7e-2fa3-3787-93cc-42f923cb0da0</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_release_id:bc52fe80-e4c6-4a4f-8b4d-689c8eacb41a</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:discogs:release:1814215</external-identifier>
</metadata>
