<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>12rec.029</identifier>
  <title>El Senor Ciuf Ciuf - As Seen From Above [12rec.029]</title>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <subject>12rec;el senor ciuf ciuf;pop;indie;dancepop;electronic</subject>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.5/</licenseurl>
  <description>i got an email from our dear friend stephane obadia. he told me about this guy from italy that calls himself after the sound of a steam train, ciuf ciuf, got it? steph was very excited bout his music and so are we.
just check the first song i feel like a clean blackboard: along with his mates matteo mohorovicich at sax &amp; clarinet and daniele dalla pellegrina at trumpet, oliviero farneti creates a surprisingly catchy and slightly surrealistic pop-song that knows about dance-music, lo-fi indierock and jazz (!). bet you'll whistle this one when you leave the house. we the ants sucks you in with his beautiful warm guitar-riffing. this song didn't leave my head for weeks! it ends with a little free-jazz woodwind-intermezzo. stunning. i think i saw a dead person walking yesterday expands olivieros sound-cosmos back to the sixties- these sweet vocal-harmonies in the middle make you think of the beach boys immediately. along with cheap synth-melodies, noisy wall-of-sound guitars and the trademark-woodwinds of matteo and daniele, by the way. demons, song seven, introduces the housy bassdrum and could have fit on the last gorillaz-album without a problem. the unspeakable chant of a collapsing universe afterwards exactly sounds like this: about nine minutes of psychedelic kraut-pop build on a small repetitive synth-motive. el senor ciuf ciuf waves hello to the early flaming lips.
indeed, this description might sound a little weird. the album doesn't! although there are a lot of moods and styles to be heard, oliviero's melodies, his voice and his sound of lo-fi homerecording hold it all together.

the beautiful artwork is an adaption of a comic short story by joey weiser from the US. the CDR-edition (limited to 50 hand-numbered copies) comes with four coloured cardboard-cards printed with the story "flight". check his homepage and order all the other mini comics, they're worth it!</description>
  <date>2006-03-06</date>
  <pick>1</pick>
  <public>1</public>
  <publicdate>2006-03-06 06:11:15</publicdate>
  <addeddate>2006-03-06 14:10:10</addeddate>
  <uploader>headquarter@12rec.net</uploader>
  <taper>oliviero farneti</taper>
  <source>www.12rec.net</source>
  <creator>oliviero farneti</creator>
  <runtime>40:37</runtime>
  <updatedate>2006-03-06 06:30:38</updatedate>
  <updater>Simon12rec.</updater>
  <collection>12rec</collection>
  <collection>netlabels</collection>
  <filesxml>Wed Sep 17 1:01:37 UTC 2014</filesxml>
  <boxid>OL100020603</boxid>
  <album>As Seen From Above</album>
  <artist>El Senor Ciuf Ciuf</artist>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_releasegroup_id:65845d84-da39-3781-91eb-c70195e3c03c</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_release_id:608bbab5-d802-4f2c-83c8-7cbdff93c666</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:discogs:release:1815418</external-identifier>
</metadata>
