<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <identifier>12rec.019</identifier>
  <type>sound</type>
  <publicdate>2005-06-29 09:43:46</publicdate>
  <creator>Stephane Obadia</creator>
  <description>when you go through the reviews stèphane received for his obadia-release with ADIM, you'll find critics being confused about how to judge his music. is it danceable, does it move my butt? might stèph even be innit for popmusic as you can always find a moment of melody to stick to? or are there more academical reasons, something about recycling, glitch-asthetics and stuff? thing is, as we here at 12rec believe, stéphane prefers fooling around with genres. if you listen to the hot new rob steady EP, you'll find him getting more abstract and experimental.

stèphane asked us not to write too much about the music, so we're just trying to give you an idea. what do you expect?

hurry to order the CDR, as first edition copies come up with a limited nice little poster to decorate your living room.</description>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.5/</licenseurl>
  <date>2005-06-28 00:00:00</date>
  <title>Rob Steady - Ask No Lies [12rec.019]</title>
  <uploader>headquarter@12rec.net</uploader>
  <addeddate>2005-06-28 06:40:14</addeddate>
  <adder>Simon12rec.</adder>
  <pick>1</pick>
  <runtime>28:56</runtime>
  <updatedate>2005-07-05 08:18:36</updatedate>
  <updater>Simon12rec.</updater>
  <notes>here is a review by  mersenne_twister ( www.undomondo.com ):

 voila, this is a nice humorous album! your beats rock! here's my review on undomondo mp3blog..

#2 is Stephane Obadia as Rob Steady on 12 Rec apparently he is a cool dude from France (but living in Stockholm as i interpreted from the website . - ha! ) He has been involved with different media all the while and this album is an interesting cut-up experience that intrigued me a lot at the first listen. After some listens, yes, this album has some brilliant moments. His beats are incredible and the album is very humorous, i am really looking forward to more releases from him. It is probably far out there for many listeners, but if shifting time signatures, sweet childish melodies, very complex arrangements or oddity is your thing, and you like music that changes every 30 seconds like hyperactive kids (which i love!) or ends abruptly you'll love this album!!!</notes>
  <source>www.12rec.net</source>
  <public>1</public>
  <publisher/>
  <taper/>
  <collection>12rec</collection>
  <collection>netlabels</collection>
  <filesxml>Wed Sep 17 1:01:37 UTC 2014</filesxml>
  <boxid>OL100020419</boxid>
  <album>Ask No Lies</album>
  <artist>Rob Steady</artist>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_releasegroup_id:b0d8e538-b4bd-3ad2-a16c-da00fd46ab7d</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_release_id:12d1957b-bdd1-41a6-9fcb-bae466931de9</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:discogs:release:1814173</external-identifier>
</metadata>
