<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>12rec.020</identifier>
  <title>Zeugwart Hallbauer - Koelner Sommer [12rec.020]</title>
  <creator>Zeugwart Hallbauer</creator>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <description>zeugwart hallbauer like to use reverb. many sounds seem to circulate in a far distance, diving in and out of the listenerÂs ear. and they create a lot of room for these sounds, still there are always walls somewhere to stop the sounds from floating into total oblivion. did somebody say these guys were playing electronica?
their music is sort of loop based, two or three main rhythmic motives and a line to carry the melody. dont get me wrong: the 'koelner sommer EP' isnÂt really minimal. zeugwart hallbauer superimpose many loops on top of each other, create swinging, even polyrhytmic patterns of synthetic melodies and grooves. you can dance to it, but you donÂt have to. you can also chill and nod your head while trying to figure out the many influences zeugwart hallbauer melt together: house and techno-music (obvious), pop and jazz, hip hop, maybe 70Âs electronic music (sometimes klaus schulze comes to my mind).

it took a while to release the EP because weÂve been waiting for the videos to be finished. hugs and kisses to matthias groebel and rick silva for their great video-works! and to amaia martiÂ­n and rui oliveira who designed the CDR-package. please check rotesonne.com with whom weÂre releasing this great EP for some detailed information and further linkage.</description>
  <date>2005-08-19 00:00:00</date>
  <year>2005</year>
  <subject>Jasmin; Rotesonne Records; Electronic</subject>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.5/</licenseurl>
  <public>1</public>
  <publicdate>2005-08-18 18:59:29</publicdate>
  <addeddate>2005-08-18 18:29:03</addeddate>
  <adder>Simon12rec.</adder>
  <uploader>headquarter@12rec.net</uploader>
  <updater>Simon12rec.</updater>
  <updater>Simon12rec.</updater>
  <updater>Simon12rec.</updater>
  <updatedate>2005-10-16 06:05:50</updatedate>
  <updatedate>2005-12-31 03:59:52</updatedate>
  <updatedate>2005-12-31 04:11:00</updatedate>
  <taper>Zeugwart Hallbauer</taper>
  <source>www.12rec.net</source>
  <runtime>31:20</runtime>
  <notes>this release contains two videos by matthias groebel and rick silva in quicktime format next to the audio-files.</notes>
  <type>sound</type>
  <publisher>Zeugwart Hallbauer</publisher>
  <updatedate>2006-10-25 14:06:08</updatedate>
  <updater>Simon12rec.</updater>
  <collection>12rec</collection>
  <collection>netlabels</collection>
  <filesxml>Wed Sep 17 1:01:39 UTC 2014</filesxml>
  <boxid>OL100020601</boxid>
  <album>Kölner Sommer</album>
  <artist>Zeugwart Hallbauer</artist>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_releasegroup_id:a17f65e3-2187-3b06-a84e-fdcddd24580a</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_release_id:82850bd5-089a-40df-8470-e85a6498dd7b</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:discogs:release:1814187</external-identifier>
</metadata>
