<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <identifier>12rec.017</identifier>
  <type>sound</type>
  <publicdate>2005-04-17 12:02:31</publicdate>
  <creator>Tupolev (Holy, Vatagin, Scholler;Schweighart)</creator>
  <description>it takes tupolev three songs and exactly 12 minutes and 17 seconds to raise their voices. and   when they do so, nothing really happens- their singing isn't meant for grapping one's attention, to carry emotion or even content. it's just a further instrument to accomplish their certain vision of contemporary avant-garde folk music. throughout that EP there is a feeling of vagueness and stumbling. 
tupolev play very slow, add a lot of time-changes and keep rolling around all common harmonies. it's a kind of jazz music, for tupolev know exactly what they're doing: song number four, called as for misery, sounding like a sad drunken sailorman walking home at five o'clock in the morning, deep minor chords, singing, fieldrec, a little drums. but boy, after seven minutes the sun seems to rise; sounds increase like the city awakens and a melody as-beautiful-as-it-can-get emerges from the depths, lasting only for a few seconds before the song ends. on the other end of the spectrum there is rnd, the song afterwards, a mathematical piece of chamber-folk, precise and perfect.

due to all mentioned musical qualities, also the tupolev-sound is awesome. the piano is dry and dusty, the drums sound everything else but fat and vocals aren't put upfront. simply perfect, no doubt!</description>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/</licenseurl>
  <date>2005-04-18 00:00:00</date>
  <title>Tupolev - Tupolev EP [12rec.017]</title>
  <uploader>headquarter@12rec.net</uploader>
  <addeddate>2005-04-17 08:51:37</addeddate>
  <adder>Simon12rec.</adder>
  <pick>0</pick>
  <runtime>33:30</runtime>
  <updatedate>2005-04-17 22:55:56</updatedate>
  <updater>Simon12rec.</updater>
  <notes>here are some reviews (some english, mostly german):

Wie lange der musikalische Weg ist, den Tupolev gegangen sind, lässt sich beim Hören ihrer Debüt- EP nicht mehr feststellen. Von den zarten Folk-Songs ihrer Anfangszeit ist aber nicht mehr viel übrig. Vielmehr positioniert sich der junge österreichische Vierer zwischen klassischen Constellation (Silver Mt. Zion) und Thrill Jockey (die sanfte jazzige Variante des Post-Rocks) Releases und wirkt dabei äußerst souverän und sicher. Die Instrumentierung der Tracks ist vielseitig und gleichzeitig reduziert, was Tupolev darüber hinaus von anderen unterscheidet: Dank des The Tupolev-Choirs meistern sie sonst oft peinliche Gesangseinlagen mehr als überzeugend und erinnern dann leicht an die ersten Platten von Aber das Leben lebt. Bei allen nun genannten Verweisen ist This is Tupolev letztendlich gerade deswegen so gut, weil die Band darauf unglaublich reif, überlegt und eigenständig wirkt. Wenn sie die Motivation nicht verlieren, lassen sich hier noch einige wunderbare Alben erwarten, und da Tupolev auch noch als Keimzelle mit vielen qualitativ ebenso hervorragenden Nebenprojekten fungiert, ist dies zum Glück nicht zu befürchten.

(9/10) Martin Mühl 
(the gap 059 / 2005) 

----------------

Sometimes what is not played is more important than the sounds played. I have no idea, who this statement is from (Ornette Coleman might be a good hint, but I really cant remember), but the holes left open by Tupolev are so big an old fashioned airplane would fit through. This wonderful debut EP has half an hour of serious and intentional noodling, lost in its own universe of the notes played and finds a perfect balance between structured composition and the liberty (or lethargy) of letting things run its own way. Thinking about it, I bet a lot of work, reworking and chipping away of superfluous parts went into the writing of these tracks. And it was well worth it. This EP is free to download on the 12rec-website.
My amazement as to how deep some musicians are able to get into sound without losing contact to a defined structure is still as big as a mountain. Just as these songs are, even if they hide underneath a soft blanket for most of the time. Tupolev, a name I rather associated with a big hunk of machinery that people always wondered about how it was able to fly at all, and did for so long nevertheless, are a young band or band-collective from Austria, who founded when they went and bought their instruments[1] some years ago. Sounds as if those years in a rehearsal space really were worth it. And also gives away that it would be impossible to hurry them into anything. A trait of character no less remarkable in our hectic modern age. Their deep, almost deadpan seriousness mixed with a natural dilettantism makes up for most of the wonders they prepare on this, their debut EP. At six songs and a little over half an hour, this record is more than just an EP, actually, but the term mini LP has become as outdated as the concept of dialling a number on a telephone.
The tracks on this record are a quite dispersed batch of ideas and well-structured musical narratives that are held together by their earnest execution. Amongst the basic piano, drum, bass / cello and guitar figures there is some field recordings of people talking in a pub, electronic noise mixed through the flowing sounds, then some vocal pieces and even one song with almost real singing verses. A bottleneck guitar straight from the first album of Sigur Ros. The intensity of a handful of musicians really listening to each other from Bohren &amp; Der Club Of Gores black album. And, while I am naming legendary records here, I bet that opening D-chord of Frigid Stars by Codeine had a major influence on Tupolev, especially in the way chords and single notes get their time to sound, vibrate and fade out. Most of the time the basic instruments play in a lose yet well-timed and defined structure, with lots of holes to be filled or purposefully left open. This looseness pays a lot for the joyfulness that is transmitted in the basically sombre and melancholic atmosphere of the songs.
 For instance, good ole mistake, the track closest to the traditional concept of a song, is like a group of musicians who stumbled upon each other accidentally in a seedy, half empty bar late at night and half drunk and decided to play one song together. Which makes Black Heart Procession sound like a tightly wound rock-band in comparison. The other song with real lyrics and singing verses, as for misery, almost topples over itself in its own somnambulence. And after all that ending with the multiple self-recordings of the Tupolev Choir acapella, where obviously the band itself loses words to describe what is going on and falls into the theoretical trap of seeing the vocals as just another instrument from the opposite side.
Sounds as if Tupolev are carving out their own unique musical niche, that sits deftly between all kinds of styles: too amateurish for modern classical music, too simple for jazz, too loose for postrock, too weird for the alternative crowd, not weird enough for the people who read The Wire (or maybe not.) Musicians daring to go their own way so self consciously always get my respect. And after having penned all of this down, I wonder if this is going to be the year for great, instrumental music (see Natsat or Dont mess with Texas for that argument) that transcends the sturdy boundaries of postrock-whatever and enjoys itself meandering into every direction it fancies. 

Georg Cracked (Cracked, 03/2005) 

-------------

Jetzt rockt auch die Wiener Vorstadt die Post. Verzeihung. Tupolev als junge Depressive sind mit der ersten EP am Start, die sieben teilweise erstaunlich frühreife Leistungen zeigt. Da hat jemand die alten Meister genau studiert und herausgefunden, was zählt: das Gefühl und das Timing, die wenigen Takte zum gerade richtigen Moment zu setzen. Eine gar nicht so einfache Übung, möchte man meinen, zu derer Bewältigung es weniger gekonnter Instrumentbeherrschung braucht, als das Talent, die richtigen Stimmungen richtig rüberbringen zu können. Der Vorteil dabei: man muss nicht wirklich gut spielen können.  
Die Tupolev EP präsentiert sich als eine Mischung aus eher vertrackt-aufbauend gemeinten Impressionen (z.B.: 8,917), die vom stets präsenten und den reduzierten Sound stark aufwertenden, immer etwas schräg klingenden Klavier dominiert werden, weniger zugänglichen Singalongs (z.B.: Good Ole Mistake), einem Männerchor (der wirklich nicht sein musste) und zwei überlangen Stücken (Garlic und As For Misery), die als gekonnte Stilübungen mit Mut zur Langsamkeit Melancholie und Verträumtheit kreuzen, gelungene, wirklich in die Tiefe gehende Melodien zwischenschalten und eigentlich die erwähnenswertesten Elemente dieser frühen Aufnahme einer frischen Truppe darstellen, die sich gleichsam an Slow Pop wie an bohrendem Death Jazz sowie der ausgeklügelten Atmosphäre-Erzeugung der sample-freudigen Kanadier und Schotten orientiert. Von der wir in Zukunft hoffentlich mehr zu hören bekommen werden.

Slawomir Teodorowicz (Echoes-Online.de / 01.04.2005)

-------------
  
TUPOLEV - dieser Name führt eindeutig in die Irre, keine Ostorientierung, kein vordergründiges Scheppern oder Krachen, sondern hintergründig subtile Klänge umschmeicheln hier das Ohr. 
Um es damit auch gleich vorwegzunehmen: TUPOLEV experimentieren, Genregrenzen sind ihnen unbekannt, sie selbst beschreiben es als Nihilistic Pop-Avantgarde oder Composed Music, beides trifft zu, ist jedoch eine höchst unvollständige Beschreibung ihres Schaffens, das Pop, Jazz, experimentelle Elemente und Improvisation umfasst.
Vergleiche für diese Band zu finden ist schwierig, von der langsamen Getragenheit der Tracks erinnern sie an SAVOY GRAND oder LOW, Teile von Rnd schlagen etwa Brücken zu SONIC YOUTH. 
Das kurze 8,917 gibt als Intro mit Klavier und jazzigen Soundlandschaften einen Vorgeschmack auf das Kommende. Garlic nimmt in seiner epischen Größe den Höhepunkt dieser EP bereits vorweg - ein düsterer und sphärischer Grundton durchzieht diese sieben Minuten, in denen Geräuschkulissen auf Akkordeon, Mundharmonika, elektronische Effekte und Klavier treffen. Wer sich auf die tiefdüstere, traurige und Hoffnungslosigkeit vermittelnde Atmosphäre dieses Songs einlässt wird nach diesen sieben Minuten tief bewegt aus fernen Sphären in die Realität zurückkehren und darf sich getrost dem folgenden Good Ole Mistake und dem ähnlich gestrickten As For Misery anvertrauen. Diese Tracks überzeugen mit noch mehr Klavier und harmonischer Dissonanz, "Good Ole Mistake" bietet erstmals einerseits Gesang und andererseits auch mal lautere und schnellere Passagen. Rnd gibt sich poppiger, verträglicher und ist auch konventioneller instrumentiert.
Überraschend letztendlich noch ., in dem a cappella ein Chor brummelt. 
Menschen die sich gerne auf unbekanntes Terrain vorwagen und auch mit experimenteller Musik etwas anfangen können werden von TUPOLEV sicherlich begeistert sein und sollten hier ohne länger zu überlegen zugreifen. 

6..5/7.0
Doris (www.earshot.at / 29.03.2005)</notes>
  <source>www.12rec.net</source>
  <taper>Tupolev</taper>
  <public>1</public>
  <subject>Chamber Music;Slow Rock;Improvisational post-modern alternative folk</subject>
  <publisher>Tupolev</publisher>
  <collection>12rec</collection>
  <collection>netlabels</collection>
  <filesxml>Wed Sep 17 1:01:39 UTC 2014</filesxml>
  <boxid>OL100020510</boxid>
  <album>Tupolev</album>
  <artist>Tupolev</artist>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_releasegroup_id:2d728411-9dbc-3300-a537-a52ddbd67d8a</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:mb_release_id:6d12ebb3-3a5f-4efd-8542-83a015f18ce3</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:discogs:release:442922</external-identifier>
  <external-identifier>urn:discogs:master:358465</external-identifier>
</metadata>
